Mss.B.V462
American Philosophical Society
- Series I: Correspondence, 1768-1922; c. 850 items.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 8, 1823; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Correia da Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Paris, 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. News concerning activity and poor health of J. Correa de Serra. Duties of E. Correa in Portuguese Foreign Department. Copy of letter printed in A.P.S. Trans., v.45, par 2, p.188. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 19, 1823; 7 3/4" x 12 5/8"; Ewing, James S.
    ----, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. With respect to a medal awarded to Mr. Ewing. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 20, 1823; 6 1/4" x 7 3/4"; Cooper, Thomas, 1759-1839
    Columbia, S.C.,A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. Presbyterian influence against him at the college. Books ordered. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, May 26, 1823; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Bogert, G. G.
    New York, 1 p. A.L.S. Introducing Professor Finch. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 21, 1823; 8" x 9 7/8"; Sully, Thomas, 1783-1872
    Baltimore, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Has been paid for his painting, "Passage of the Delaware." Encloses draft for $450. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 1, 1823; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Correia de Serra, José Francisco, 1750-1823
    Paris, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Reflections upon politics as a profession. Condition of Portugal. Printed: Davis, Abbé Correa, APS Trans n.s.45, pt.2, 1955, 189. Formerly MISC. MS. COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 27, 1823; 8" x 10"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Montecello, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Finances in connection with importations. FILM 199 FRAME 272 MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 24, 1823; 8" x 9 3/4"; Physick, Philip Syng, 1768-1837
    C-1 Philadelphia, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Thanks Vaughan for box of claret. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, October 9, 1823; 8" x 9 7/8"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. John Baring. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, October 26, 1823; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Vaughan, Samuel
    Jamaica, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Forwards statement of accounts. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 9, 1823; 7 3/8" x 8 7/8"; Ware, Henry, 1764-1845
    Boston, 4 pp. and address. A.L.S. Discussion of the constitution of the [Unitarian?] churches. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 17, 1824; 7 1/8" x 8 3/4"; Ware, Nathaniel A., ca. 1790-1854
    New York, 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. Returns thanks for pleasure of his visit to Philadelphia. Heard a lecture by Mr. Bancroft yesterday. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 30, 1824; 7 3/4" x 9 5/8"; Browne, Peter A. (Peter Arrell), 1782-1860
    Philadelphia, 2 pp., address and endorsement. Pr.L.S. Circular concerning a collection of the rocks and minerals of Pennsylvania. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 10, 1824; 7 3/8" x 8 7/8"; Ware, Henry, 1794-1843
    Boston, 1 p.and address. A.L.S. Has sent to Vaughan a small trunk for Reuben Haines. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 5, 1824; 9x7-3/4; Gilmer, Francis Walker, 1790-1826
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. Returns thanks for letters. Will embark at New York on the 8th. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 8, 1824; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Storer, J. P. B.
    Baltimore, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Has just returned from Washington. Will be in Philadelphia on Wednesday. "Mr. Adams' prospects look brighter [every?] day..." Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 13, 1824; Anonymous
    Invitation to funeral of Mrs. Singleton of South Carolina. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 29, 1824; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Ware, Henry, 1794-1843
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Acknowledges letter of 26th. Will send somebody to take the place of Mr. Storer to June 27th. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Aug. 9, 1824; 8" x 10"; Sparks, Jared, 1789-1866
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Acknowledges Mr. Sergeant's subscription. Asks for autographs of Washington, Franklin and Rittenhouse. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 27, 1824; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Swift, J. G.
    New York, 2 pp. and address. Printed form L. with ms. notation. Regarding dissolution of U.S. Military and Philosophical Society and use of its funds by Lyceum of Natural History in New York. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 6, 1824; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    Hallowell, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Miss Emma Jane Gardiner, who is traveling with Ticknor and his wife. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 16, 1824; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Ware, Henry, 1764-1845
    Cambridge, (Mass.), 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Regarding the publication of pamphlets to assist the cause of Christianity in India. Mentions ordination of Mr. Furness. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 22, 1825; 7 7/8" x 9 5/8"; Gardiner, R. M.
    Portland, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. and Mrs. Richard Cobb. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Jno. Vaughan, April 12, 1825; 7 7/8" x 9"; Appleton, C. H.
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing the Rev. Mr. Robinson, of Eastport. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 23, 1825; 7 7/8" x 10"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Captain Gordon of the Royal Artillery. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John [Vaughan], May 18, 1825; 8" x 9 15/16"; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850
    London, 1 p. Duplicate of A.L.S. Enclosing letter from Davies Gilbert upon the subject of weights and measures. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 5, 1825; 8" x 10"; Bancroft, George, 1800-1891
    West Point, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. Relative to finding a Spanish teacher for [Round Hill School]. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 4, 1825; 7 1/4" x 8 1/2"; Furness, William Henry, 1802-1896
    Cambridge, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing the Rev. George R. Noyes. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to C[harles] N[icoll] Bancker, Aug. 12, 1825; 10x8; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see John Vaughan papers.) Forwards certificate of membership and Transactions of the APS. Asks him to be certain to attend a meeting which pertains to the Academy. Presented by Earl E. Moore; Feb. 1965. 1965 125ms. Formerly B V462.3.
  - Memorandum, August 19(?), 1825; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letterto John Vaughan, September 20, 1825; 7 3/4" x 9 5/8"; Cleaveland, Parker, 1780-1858
    Brunswick, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Terms for a lecturer on the theory and practice of physic at Medical School. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Oct. 19, 1825; 8" x 9 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Duties on marble imported from Italy. "Written with a disorder'd polygraph." FILM 199 FRAME 273 MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Oct. 30, 1825; 8" x 9 3/4"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and add. end. Asks aid in finding a brewer for the University. FILM 199 FRAME 274 MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 9, 1826; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Coles, Edward, 1786-1868
    Vandalia, Illinois, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Regarding corrections made upon a small map of Illinois, sent to him by John Vaughan. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 16, 1826; 7 1/4" x 8 7/8"; Everett, Oliver
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Sends a copy of Christian Examiner to Vaughan. Has given agency of this paper to Mr. Small. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 24, 1826; 7 3/4" x 9 1/2"; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Monticello, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Introduces his grandson, T.J. Randolph, who goes to Philadelphia in connection with sale of Jefferson's property. FILM 199 FRAME 295 MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 4, 1826; 7 1/4" x 9 1/4"; Vaughan, Charles B., 1759-1839
    Washington, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Mulberry tree of Virginia. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 6, 1826; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Cooper, Thomas, 1759-1839
    Columbia, S. C., 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Col. Thomas Taylor coming to Philadelphia because of his daughter's illness. State of his own health. Dissatisfied with students at his college. Family news. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 6, 1826; 7 5/8" x 9 1/2"; Everett, Edward, 1794-1865
    Washington, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Requests Vaughan to send enclosed letter to the Mexican minister. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 11, 1826; 8" x 10"; Biddle, James, 1783-1848
    Norfolk, A.L.S. 3p. and add.,end. Naval appointments. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 13, 1826; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854
    London, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Burnley, senior member of His Majesty's Council in Trinidad. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 24, 1826; 7 3/4" x 9 5/8"; Cooper, Thomas, 1759-1839
    Columbia, S.C., 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Enclosure: newspaper clipping, n.d. With regard to the estate of the late Thomas Jefferson, and the affairs of Mrs. Randolph. FILM 199 FRAME 430. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, August 16, 1826; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Mease, James, 1771-1846
    Philadelphia, 3 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Regarding falsification of boundary line on Arrowsmith's map of the United States. Refers to Correia de Serra and Lord Hawkesbury. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaugh[a]n, August 20, 1826; 5" x 8"; Stevenson, John B.
    New York, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Dr. P. S. Townsend. Refers to Robert vaux and the prison. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, October 9, 1826; 8" x 10"; Thornely, Thomas
    L-3 Liverpool, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing the Rev. D. W. Jones. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 18, 1826; 7 7/8" x 9 1/2"; Everett, Edward, 1794-1865
    New York, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Encloses letter to Miss Boyd, with regard to furnished lodgings for him. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 1, 1826; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Channing, William Ellery, 1780-1842
    New York, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Introducing David William Jones, "who has come among us to be a teacher of the ancient classics." Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Verses for John Vaughan, 1826; 8" x 10"; Furness, William Henry, 1802-1896
    D. 1p. and add., end. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 4, 1827; 2 1/2" x 7 7/8"; Fraser, Anna L.
    Philadelphia, 1 p. D.S. Promissory note for $100. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 22, 1827; Walsh, Robert, Jr.
    Introducing W. M. Sprague, collector of pamphlets. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 26, 1827; 7 15/16" x 9 15/16"; Bancroft, Aaron, 1755-1839
    Worcester, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing George Bancroft. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 26, 1827; 7 3/8" x 8 7/8"; Ticknor, George, 1791-1871
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Bancroft, of Northampton, "who is about to visit Philadelphia with his Bride." Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 28, 1827; 7 15/16" x 9"; Apthorp, Joseph T.
    Boston, 1 p., address and endorsement. Introducing his son, Leonard F. Apthorp. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 1, 1827; 7 5/8" x 9 1/2"; Allen, Benjamin, 1789-1829
    Hyde Park, 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Information with regard to his school for boys. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, July 30, 1827; S.G.P.
    Regarding an essay on an insect that destroys grape vine that he sent to the National Gazette. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, August 9, 1827; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Farley, Frederick A. (Frederick Augustus), 1800-1892
    Washington, 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. Announcing the death of the Rev. Robert Little. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, August 21, 1827; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; God---, Joseph D.
    New York, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Dr. Anderson, professor of mathematics at Columbia College. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 6, 1827; 7 7/8" x 9 1/2"; Trist, Nicholas Philip, 1800-1874
    Monticello, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Regarding affairs of Thomas Jefferson Randolph, such as debt to him owed by the state of Louisiana. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Robert Vaughan, September 14, 1827; 7 5/8" x 12 3/4"; Duncan, J. M.
    Hagerstown, Md., 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Wishes to sell a German Bible, in three volumes, dated 1589, 1591, and 1592. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, October 5, 1827; 7 3/4" x 9 1/2"; Adrain, Robert, 1775-1843
    N[ew] B[runswick], N. J., 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Thanks Vaughan for "the letter of anticipation relative to my appointment" to the faculty of the University of Pennsylvania. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, October 10, 1827; 7 15/16" x 10 1/16"; Harris, Levett
    Paris, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Baron de Krudener, Russian minister to the United States. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, October 22, 1827; 7 5/8" x 9 5/8"; Washington, Bushrod, 1762-1829
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Encloses a letter from a friend (missing) making certain inquiries (not indicated) upon which Vaughan's opinion is requested. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 7, 1827; 6 3/8" x 8"; Washington, Bushrod, 1762-1829
    ----, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Requests that Mr. Vaughan answer his letter of ten days ago. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 4, 1828; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Bulfinch, Charles, 1763-1844
    Washington, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Dr. and Mrs. Frederick Hall. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 7, 1828; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Gallaudet, F. H.
    Hartford, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Forwards a set of the annual reports of the asylum. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 8, 1828; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Everett, Edward, 1794-1865
    Winterhill, Charlestown, [Mass.], 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Charles Folsom. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Jno. Vaughan, September 3, 1828; 7 7/8" x 10"; Pierpont, John, 1785-1866
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. John Frost. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, December 22, 1828; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Stevenson, A.
    Washington, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Requests Vaughan to investigate " the state of the carriage" he had ordered built in Philadelphia. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Dec. 27, 1828; 8" x 9 1/2"; Bowditch, Nathaniel, 1773-1838
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Desires table of rates used by the Philadelphia Life Insurance Co. to issue life annuities. Is printing his translation of La Place's Mec. Cel.; will present copy to Philosophical society. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 2, 1829; 8" x 9 3/4"; Van Rensselaer, Jeremiah, 1793-1871
    New York, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Informs Vaughan of his election as a corresponding member of the Lyceum of Natural History. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Jno. Vaughan, March 5, 1829; 8" x 10 1/8"; Poinsett, Joel Roberts, 1779-1851
    Mexico, 1 p. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Del Rio. "of whom honorable mention is made by Baron [Alexander von] Humboldt." Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 8, 1829; 7 1/4" x 9 1/2"; Vidua, Carlo, 1785-1830
    Macao, A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. His travels. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 25, 1829; 6" x 8 1/4"; Royal Academy of History (Spain)
    Librarian of A.P.S., Madrid, 1 p. L.S. (In Spanish.) Informs Vaughan of his election to corresponding membership in the Royal Academy of History of Spain. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 10, 1829; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Royal Academy of Sciences (Turin, Italy)
    Librarian of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. L.S. (In French.) Informs Vaughan of his nomination to corresponding membership in the Royal Academy of Sciences of Turin. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, August 6, 1829; 7 13/16" x 9 11/16"; Cleaveland, Parker, 1780-1858
    Bowdoin College 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. James Nisley. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 15, 1829; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Anderson, Henry J.
    New York, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Lorenzo da Ponte. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to [John Vaughan?], Oct. 7, 1829; 10-1/4x8-1/4; Julius, N. H. (Nicolaus Heinrich), 1783-1862
    Hamburg, A.L.S. 3p. Hopes Vaughan has recovered from accident. Interest in America. Opposition to slavery. Wishes to be remembered to friends at the APS. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Oct. 13, 1829; 10x8; Abbott, Jacob, 1803-1879
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p.and add. Regarding the purchase of electrical equipment in Philadelphia for the use of a school in Boston. Film 403 Frame 27. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to Jno. Vaughan, Oct. 15, 1829; 8" x 10"; Poinsett, Joel Roberts, 1779-1851
    Mexico, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. His collection of antiquities [probably sent to APS]. In connection with Mr. Keating has made a collection of the cactus plants of Mexico. Freeman Guide 2185. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, October 29, 1829; 8" x 9 7/8"; Farley, Frederick A. (Frederick Augustus), 1800-1892
    New York, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Personal affairs. Forwards letter by his brother, who will pass through Philadelphia on his way to St. Louis. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to J[ohn] Vaughan, December 19, 1829; 6" x 8"; Lesueur, Charles Alexandre, 1778-1846
    New Harmony, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. (In French.) Introducing Dr. [John?] Bell. MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 8, 1830; 7 1/8" x 8 7/8"; Bancroft, George, 1800-1891
    Northampton, [Mass.], 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing his brother-in-law, Mr. Dwight. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 22, 1830; 8" x 10"; Gardiner, R. M.
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Conte Vitaliano dal Verone. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 26, 1830; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Société française de statistique.
    Secretary of A.P.S., Paris, 1 p., address and endorsement. Pr.D.Signed: Cesar Moreau. (In French.) Proposing John Vaughan as an honorary foreign member of the Société. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 5, 1830; 8" x 10"; Bowditch, Nathaniel, 1773-1838
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Desires to borrow volume from the library of the Philosophical society. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 21, 1830; 7 1/8" x 9 7/8"; Upham, Charles Wentworth, 1802-1875
    Washington, 1 p. A.L.S. Would be glad to have Mr. Barry take his place on May 2 or 9, to preach to his congregation. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, June 23, 1830; 8" x 10"; White, D. A.
    Salem, 2pp. and address. A.L.S. Encloses pamphlets for Vaughan, DuPonceau, and Furness. Reasons for taking part in the lyceum movement. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, September 25, 1830; 8" x 9 7/8"; Ware, Henry, 1794-1843
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Thanks Vaughan for attending to a box of his books at the custom house. Saw William Vaughan when in London. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, Oct. 16, 1830; 8" x 9 3/4"; Haslam, John
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Account of a live toad found buried in a stone. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 5, 1830; 7 7/8" x 9"; Vaughan, John A.
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Gorham Abbott. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, November 21, 1830; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Quincy, Josiah, 1772-1864
    Cambridge, [Mass.], 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Josiah Quincy, Jr., and the only son of his friend, Jonathan Phillips, a lad of ten, coming to Philadelphia for medical treatment. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to [John] Vaughan, Dec. 16, 1830; 8" x 10"; Monroe, James, 1758-1831
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. Sends copies for Mr. Vaughan and the [APS] library of [S.L.] Gouverneur's oration on the revolution in France. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to john Vaughan, Dec. 28, 1830; Physick, Philip Syng, 1768-1837
    Thanks for volume and introduction to Mr. Furness. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 11, 1831; 8" x 9 7/8"; Sullivan, William
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. James Furbish, of Portland. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, January 26, 1831; 4 13/16" x 7 7/8"; Hentz, Nicholas Marcellus, 1797-1856
    Univ. of North Carolina, 2 pp. A.L.S. Forwards a tragedy to Vaughan, to be sent to Mr. W. Pelby, the actor, for a possible $500 premium. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 7, 1831; 7 7/8" x 10"; Goodacre, Robert, fl. 1847
    London, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Herbert Holthum. Regarding Mr. John Gregory. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 17, 1831; 7 15/16" x 9 5/8"; Hassler, F. R. (Ferdinand Rudolph), 1770-1843
    Washington, 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Concerning observations upon an eclipse. Naval committee has proposed the renewal of the coast survey law of 1807. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, February 19, 1831; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; Channing, William Ellery, 1780-1842
    St. Croix, 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of two letters. Fine climate of St. Croix. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 9, 1831; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Quincy, Josiah, 1772-1864
    Cambridge, [Mass.], 2 pp. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. Benjamin D. Greene. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letterr to John Vaughan, April 5, 1831; 7 3/8" x 9"; Ticknor, George, 1791-1871
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Introducing Mr. [C. C.] Felton, a Greek tutor in Cambridge. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 26, 1831; 8" x 10"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Desires information about a certain kind of silk. MADEIRA-VAUGHAN COLLECTION
  - Letter to John Vaughan, April 27, 1831; 8" x 9 3/4"; Farley, Frederick A. (Frederick Augustus), 1800-1892
    Providence, 3 pp. and address. A.L.S. Regarding the formation of an Athenaeum at Providence. Progress of Unitarian Church. Wishes to be remembered to his friends in Philadelphia. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, May 9, 1831; 8" x 10 1/8"; Flagg, J. F.
    Boston, 1 p. and address. A.L.S. Intends to visit Philadelphia with his wife. Requests Vaughan to Obtain a room at home of Mrs. Eaton. Formerly MISC MS COLLECTION.